There's More Than One Way To Keep A Marriage Together...
House Arrest is a comedy, family film directed by Harry Winer.
High-schooler Grover Beindorf and his younger sister Stacy decide that their parents, Janet and Ned, are acting childishly when they
decide to divorce after 18 years of marriage, so they lock them up in the basement until they'll sort out their problems.
Janet Beindorf, played by Jamie Lee Curtis.
Ned Beindorf, played by Kevin Pollak.
Gregory Alan 'Grover' Beindorf, played by Kyle Howard.
Brooke Figler, played by Jennifer Love Hewitt.
Cindy Figler, played by Jennifer Tilly.
Donald Krupp, played by Christopher McDonald.
House Arrest is a 1996 American comedy film directed by Harry Winer, written by Michael Hitchcock, and starring Jamie Lee Curtis,  Kevin Pollak, Jennifer Tilly, Christopher
McDonald, Wallace Shawn, and Ray Walston, with Kyle Howard, Amy Sakasitz, Mooky Arizona, Russel Harper, and an up-and-coming Jennifer Love Hewitt in supporting roles.
It tells the story of two children who lock their parents in the basement upon their plans for a separation as the
other children they know get involved by locking their respective problem parents in there as well.
The film was produced by Rysher Entertainment and released by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer on
August 14, 1996, and went on to gross just over $7 million at the box office.
It was panned by critics.
The film was shot at various locations in the U.S.
states of California and Ohio.
Monrovia, California was the location for several exterior house scenes while most
interior shots were done at the CBS/Radford lot in Studio City, California.
The story was set in Defiance, Ohio, although Chagrin
Falls, Ohio actually doubled for it.
The tone is lighthearted.